education.vic.gov.au 2010-06-10

# Privacy Statement - Department of Education and Early Childhood Development

The Department of Education and Early Childhood Development (DEECD) is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. This  Online Privacy Statement governs the collection, storage, use, access and disposal of data including all personal information obtained on DEECD websites. Please take some time to read through this statement and understand our position on privacy.

This privacy statement will be updated from time to time so please visit this page regularly.

This Privacy Statement does not apply to linked websites that are not DEECD sites. When you link to another site we recommend you read the privacy statement of that site.

The Department has an information privacy policy and handles personal information in accordance with the Victorian Privacy laws: the _Information Privacy Act 2000_ and _Health Records Act 2001_. This policy is available on request and the policy can be accessed online.

##  Collection of Information

Two types of online data are collected by DEECD:

  1. Visitor logs and statistics 
  2. Information provided by users through online forms, registration, databases and feedback (When personal information is collected online through for example databases and forms, a privacy notice informing you how your personal information will be collected, used and protected will be available). 

###  Visitor logs and statistics

DEECD sites gather statistics on users’ online experience. Information collected includes:

  * Visitor server addresses and domains 
  * The times and dates the site was visited 
  * The pages visitors accessed and files downloaded 
  * Visitors’ browsers and operating systems. 

The main purpose for collecting this information is to provide statistical information used for website and system administration. The information does not identify individual users but does identify the computer that is used to access our sites.

Logged information is not disclosed outside of DEECD staff or those under contract to conduct maintenance to web server components. We make no attempt to identify individuals from these records unless it is necessary to the investigation of a breach of law.

###  User Information

Some Department sites require visitors to provide personal information when they engage in online activities such as subscribing to conferences, participating in DEECD email discussion groups, registering online for education activities, completing online forms and feedback. Personal information collected may include a visitor’s first and last name, postal address, email address, employer, job title and department, telephone and fax numbers. The Department will inform you how your personal information will be used at the point of collection.

###  Internet Risks

Any personal information collected is used for the purpose of providing online services and monitoring these. All Department staff have a legal duty to protect the privacy of your personal information and ensure it is used only for the purpose to which you have agreed. DEECD does not make available users' personal information to other organisations or individuals. Personal information is handled in accordance with Victorian privacy legislation and is stored and disposed of in accordance with Department's [Record Keeping Policy](http://www.education.vic.gov.au/management/governance/archivesandrecords/schoolrecordspermanent.htm). 

There are inherent risks associated with the transmission of personal information via the internet as it is not a secure medium. Do not provide any secure personal information online such as a password or credit card number or information that you wish to keep confidential. To understand these risks read the information on the [Australian Internet Safety Advisory Body website](http://www.netalert.gov.au/) (http://www.netalert.gov.au/).

The Department has made every effort to implement security policies, rules and measures to protect your information from unauthorised access, improper use, alteration and destruction.

See also the DEECD Information and Communication Technology Security policy.

The Department does not guarantee secure transmission of data transmitted via its websites. If you have any concerns providing the personal information asked for please call the Online Communications Unit on 03 9657 2626 and we can make arrangements to suit you.

If you would like more information or to access or upgrade your personal information, please Contact the Department of Education and Early Childhood Development.

##  Use of Authenticated DEECD websites

The Department secure websites, which require a username and password for access verification, gather information on a user’s online experiences through the use of a visitor’s username. Please keep your access codes secure and do not share them.

##  Cookies and web scripts on DEECD websites

'Cookies' are small text files that are generated by our servers and stored onto your computer. They allow us to recognise when you return to certain sites and allow us to register user preferences.

DEECD does not generally build websites that involve the use of cookies. On DEECD websites that do use cookies, a cookie is sent from our server and automatically placed on your computer without notification. Personal preferences or information may be stored in the cookie, which is then sent back to the server on completion of the session. Cookies may be turned off within your browser, however, this may make some sites unusable.

More information can be found on the [Wikipedia page about HTTP cookies](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie) (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie)

Pages on the site may be coded with Omniture's SiteCatalyst HBX software. This is transparent to the user, as the software makes use of an invisible image at the bottom of the web page. This software stores a cookie in your browser, which contains a unique identifier, and sends information to SiteCatalyst HBX. This enables SiteCatalyst HBX to track the number of unique visitors to the site. In no way does this unique identifier identify a user personally.

  * See the Omniture website about their [privacy practices](http://www.omniture.com/privacy) (http://www.omniture.com/privacy) or find out specific information about  [SiteCatalyst HBX](http://www.omniture.com/products/web_analytics/sitecatalyst) (http://www.omniture.com/products/web_analytics/sitecatalyst).

##  Online Privacy Statement Comments

DEECD welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Statement. If you believe that any DEECD division, website or employee has not adhered to this Statement please contact DEECD by email, fax, or mail.

Department of Education and Early Childhood Development

Online and Corporate Communications Branch

Level 1, 2 Treasury Place

East Melbourne VIC 3002

Fax: 03 9657 2626

Email: [webinfo@edumail.com.au](mailto:webinfo@edumail.com.au?Subject=Privacy%20Statement%20enquiry)

For further information regarding privacy, view the [_Victorian Information Privacy Act 2000_](http://www.legislation.vic.gov.au/Domino/Web_Notes/LDMS/PubStatbook.nsf/f932b66241ecf1b7ca256e92000e23be/4BE13AE4A4C3973ECA256E5B00213F50/$FILE/00-098a.pdf) (http://www.legislation.vic.gov.au/) or go to the [Privacy Victoria website](http://www.privacy.vic.gov.au/) (http://www.privacy.vic.gov.au/).
